

💌 samueltorimiro1@gmail.com | 🎁 www.samueltorimiro.info | 🖸 Samuel-2626 | 🛅 samuel-torimiro

Summary _

As an experienced software engineer and technical writer with over two years of industry experience, I possess a unique combination of technical expertise and communication skills. I have developed a deep understanding of software development principles and have honed my abilities to write clear, concise, and effective technical documentation.

Skills_

Languages Python, JavaScript (Link), PHP (Link), SQL

Backend Frameworks Django (Link) Frontend Frameworks React (Link) Databases Postgres, MySQL

Technical Writing Conceptual documentation, Detailed integration guides, Code samples, Docsy, Hugo

Others Docker, AWS, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Heroku, cPanel

Work Experience _____

Tridens Technology Slovenia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & TECHNICAL WRITER

July 2022 - Date

- · Created and maintained Tridens Monetization, EV Charge, and EV Charge Mobile App documentation.
- · Followed Google developer documentation style guide to make the technical documentation industry standard.
- · Broke down complex user interface interactions into easy-to-understand manuals/instructions that customers can understand.
- · Worked directly with the Product manager, COO, and CTO to understand each product and technical needs.
- Performed front-end design on the user interface of the technical documentation.

Draft.dev 1154

TECHNICAL WRITER Sept. 2021 - Aug. 2022

- Researched and wrote technical content that resonated with developers.
- Featured in top tech companies' blogs, including Strapi, Replit, and Amadeus.
- Created follow-along tutorials in popular languages and frameworks like Node.js and Django.

Educative Inc. IISA

PYTHON/DJANGO COURSE INSTRUCTOR

Oct. 2021 - Feb. 2022

Nov. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Developed a text-based course titled Build robust applications with test-driven development in Django.
- Explained in-depth the differences between unit, integration, and functional tests.
- · Discussed the five steps involved in test-driven development which can be summed up to the "Red, Green, Refactor" process.
- Built a Django project from scratch using the test-driven development approach.

Testdriven.io 11SA

TECHNICAL WRITER May 2021 - Jan. 2022

- Created several articles covering important topics of the Django web framework.
- Followed a project-based tutorial approach for most articles.
- Broke down complex subjects into easy-to-understand materials.

REACH Technologies

• Developed a collaborative backend service similar to Slack or Microsoft Teams.

- · Created several API endpoints using the Django REST framework.
- Turned the backend service to be asynchronous and in real-time using Django Channels.

Projects

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Nesa Academy

PYTHON & JAVASCRIPT

- Developed a question-and-answer platform called Nesa Academy, similar to Stack Overflow but for economists.
- Users can gain reputations as they give correct answers to questions.
- · Users can share and follow the questions they like.

Technical Articles

- 2021 **Testdriven.io**, Basic and Full-text Search with Django and Postgres (Link)
- 2021 **Testdriven.io**, Supporting multiple languages in Django (Link)
- 2021 **Section.io**, How to send emails in Django (Link)
- 2021 **Section.io**, Build a Contact Form with PHP (Link)
- 2021 **Section.io**, Full-Stack Reactive Website in Django (Link)
- 2021 **Replit**, Deploy Django to Replit (Link)
- 2022 **Testdriven.io**, Pagination in Django (Link)
- 2022 **Strapi**, Implementing Authenticated API Requests in Strapi (Link)
- 2022 **Amadeus**, Build a flight booking application with Angular and Node.js (Link)
- 2022 Rapyd, PHP Payment Gateway Integration with Rapyd (Link)

Honors & Awards

2021 **Finalist**, Al for Energy Hackathon [Data Science Nigeria]

Lagos, Nigeria

Certificates

2021 CS50x: CS50's Introduction to Computer Science and the art of Programming, edX

Education

UNIOSUN(Osun State University)

B.Sc. IN ECONOMICS